# **Kevin Torrington**

I've been designing digital and offline experiences for over 10 years. From my days of running a city center photography studio, and founding an events company, to now creating software products the people love to use, I have always held to the belief that empathy is the key to success.

07498732688 kevin.torrington@gmail.com www.kevintorrington.co.uk Manchester, UK

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Arctic Shores** — Senior UX Designer

Feb. 2020 - Present

#### UNA

The goal of this project was to redesign the MVP version of a self-service psychrometric assessment platform. The platform allows Arctic Shores clients to create behavior-based assessments in the form of fun video games.

#### Interview Guide

The goal of this project was to design a system that generates interview questions, based upon a candidate's psychrometric performance, in the form of a PDF.

## **Electrika Ltd** — Lead UX Designer, Product Manager 2015 - Jan, 2020

#### OneTime - Product Information Management Web App

The goal of this project was to rethink how manufacturers and retailers approached product information management. PIM software is not new, but most products in the market fall short with their user experience. With complex user journeys and the inability to allow users to make large changes, it was clear the market was ready for something new.

#### Schneider Electric - Estimating Software iPad and Web App

The goal of this project was to replace an outdated lotus notes enterprise estimating software, used by over 200 field service engineers with an Ipad and web app version. It needed to help the department increase upsell, improve accuracy and traceability.

Most importantly it needed to as frictionless as possible as engineers had in the past chosen not to bother quoting as the old system was slow, hard to use and often wrong.

#### British Gas - Site Survey iPad and Web App

The goal of this project was to prototype a site survey app for a new

#### **SKILLS**

Visual Design

Design System Creation

Interaction Design

Card Sorting

Wireframing

Prototyping

User Research

**Empanty Maps** 

Information Architecture

**UX** Leadership

Team Leading

Scrum Master

Sprint Board Admin

Kanban Board Admin

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

HTML / CSS

**Javascript** 

Bootstrap

Material Design

Angular (basic)

#### **AWARDS**

Professional Diploma in UX

Design - UX Design Institute

**Business Management NVQ** 

Level 2 - JP Training

exciting business unit within Centrica / British gas. It would allow engineers to pre-qualify jobs through the use of chatbots and artificial intelligence and image recognition to consider feasibility before travelling to the site to improve profitably and accuracy.

This exciting new product (product details redacted due to NDA) is to be piloted with just a few engineers. If proved successful, then it would be rolled out to all 6,000.

#### Electrika - Product Search Web App

The goal of this project was to completely redesign and reposition a niche ageing estimating tool into a more mainstream online product library that would have broad appeal by the construction industry as a whole.

The new product needed to be mobile responsive, fast and easy to use while working on construction sites but most importantly it needed to grow product impressions by at least 80% within 12 months.

#### Unitrunk - Product Website Web App

The goal of this project was to completely replace Unitrunks outdated static website with a new product-focused site.

It needed to be fast, easy to navigate and give the user the ability to download technical information, such as product datasheets.

The site also needed to include a content management system to allow staff to update news and content but most importantly the site needed to have great usability and SEO.

# **Wenso Ltd** — Head of UX Design, Product Manager 2013 - 2014

#### Four Magazine - Content Management System Web App

Responsible for research, design and project management of a bespoke content management system/enterprise resource planning tool for a print publishing company. I oversaw an outsourced development team based in India using the agile methodology.

## **B Lucky Casino Hire** — *Head of UX Design*, Owner 2009 - 2013

I founded and ran a small events company for over five years.

We specialised in casino themed events for the corporate hospitality and wedding market, averaging about 375 events per year.

This is where my love for user-centred design started, from collecting feedback from customers to improving my customer service to A/B testing of user journeys and the information architecture of the website.

As most of my traffic came from organic search and Adwords, I know how important SEO, website analytics and goal conversion can be.

#### **TOOLS**

Adobe XD

Sketch

**Figma** 

InVision

Porotopie

Axure RP

After Effects

Premier Pro

Illustrator

Photoshop

Confluence

**IIRA** 

Visual Studio Code

**GIT** 

#### **HOBBIES**

Dungeons and Dragons Musical Theater Board Games Video Games

#### **EDUCATION**

### **UX Design Institute** — Professional Diploma in UX Design

2019 - 2019

**JP Training** — Business Management NVQ Level 2

2012 - 2013

**Bedminster Down School** — *GCSE*'s

1997 - 2000